so one of the most common questions that
i get is
john do you have any recommendations for
teaching resources or
books and the answer is most certainly
yes
now i'm eventually going to be offering
my own course very soon this is the
first time that i've publicly announced
this
so keep an eye out for that but in the
meantime i'm going to show you some of
the books that i have found
incredibly helpful in sort of developing
my design sensibilities throughout the
years
one thing i want to mention is that the
books that i'm about to recommend to you
can actually be bought if you click the
links in the description
down below if you click the links in the
description down below it actually gives
me a small commission
and it doesn't cost you anything extra
so if you want to buy these books
this is a really good way for you to get
the book and also support this channel
so that i can continue to create more
content
once again i would really appreciate it
if you did that of course no pressure
only buy the books if you actually want
them
now the books that i'm about to
recommend are actually books that i have
personally read
i think i've read every single one of
them in their entirety except for one
there's one book
that i've read maybe like half of and
i'll mention that specific one
so the first book that i want to talk
about is a book called design of
everyday things
by don norman this book is amazing
this is probably one of the best primers
on industrial design
ux design etc etc there's actually a
revised edition that covered more
digital examples as well sometime in the
middle
i think around 2015 or so and this is a
really good book you'll notice that you
know i've like marked the crap
out of it i don't know if you can see
from here but you know everything is
marked up i have a ton of notes on this
i think that this is a really great book
and i actually
cite it quite a few times throughout my
videos so this is a really really good
primer on the fundamentals of industrial
design i highly recommend it to anyone
the next book i want to talk about is
called designing for growth oh there's a
piece of paper in here
space fan anyway the next book i
recommend
is called designing for growth this is a
really really great book and
basically it provides a toolkit for
design through the lens of growing a
business and this is really really
important if you want to move beyond
just
pixel pushing in your career
this is how you do it read this book it
talks to you about
how to go through ideation processes and
design thinking through the lens of
how to help a business it's actually
specifically a design thinking tool kit
for managers
but i also think it's a really really
great uh sort of primer on design
thinking for you know your average
industrial designer
the next book we have here is actually
quite similar it's called
value proposition design now this book
is quite similar to designing for growth
it basically creates
it basically talks about several ways to
come up with
value propositions and make viable
businesses through the lens of design
thinking
this book is a little bit more
illustrative like they show more
graphs and tables and stuff like that um
it
is a little bit more focused on
the business of design but it's really
really good
if you're like a more junior designer
and you want to sort of make it to that
next level
even if you're a student if you're
thinking about these things
for your next internship it's going to
put you in a good position to basically
succeed
in your career if you understand the
underlying business principles of how
design can
serve a company the next book i want to
talk about is a little bit different
this book is called elements of design
and
it's basically chronicling the work of
rowena reed costello and she is pretty
much
one of the big sort of contributors to
formal modern design education she was a
professor at pratt institute for
the better part of several decades the
better part of the 20th century
basically
and this book basically chronicles a lot
of her work
a lot of the work that i've done in
these videos when i talk about like the
silhouette sub shapes and details
are based on these principles in this
book now it's a little bit high level
and because it's sort of like a
secondhand account um it's by gail greet
hannah
it's not by rowena reed costello because
of that it's not
super complete but it's still really
cool i highly recommend it
it sort of gives some good fundamental
design advice that i would recommend
and it's just good to know who rowena
reed costello was
as a designer the next book we're going
to talk about
is manufacturing processes for
design professionals now this is the
book that i have not read all of if you
look at it it's very thick
and i have read a lot of it but
it's pretty cool basically it goes
through
just about every manufacturing process
you could imagine
has a lot of pictures and it actually
goes through several case studies
throughout the book
and it talks about like you know when
you would use these processes
and all that kind of stuff so if you're
trying to understand materials in
manufacturing and how to build things
this is a great book to look at this is
really important because if you're
trying to get a job as an industrial
designer
it's very important that you understand
how things are made
now obviously the mechanical engineers
are going to be the ones who sort of
uh send out the final factory drawings
to the manufacturer or
you know they're basically going to sign
off on the final manufactured files
but you still need to understand this
stuff because
what can happen is the engineers will be
making the design decisions and that's
it's going to end very poorly trust me
so the better you understand
manufacturing
the better you will be as a designer i
highly recommend manufacturing processes
for
design professionals and then the last
book i want to talk about is a little
different
um this is just called design
the definitive visual history it's by
smithsonian
now this one is really interesting
because it basically
talks about every single industrial
design and architectural movement of the
past
several hundred years and it's sort of
like
a basic primer of everything that has
happened
in that time like i just sort of opened
up to streamlining here
so this is streamlining and it talks
about
every single design movement that
happened and what the cultural and
historical context was
and what each legacy was for each of
these movements and it talks about
individual designers as well i highly
recommend it
it is a little bit surface level because
it's covering you know hundreds of years
of history
but it's sort of a good primer it's a
good sort of like
introduction to each of these various
design movements i highly recommend this
as well
so that pretty much covers the books
that i wanted to discuss
there are some other design
tools that i use and probably the
biggest one is the ballpoint pen and i
actually have one right here
so this is the schneider slider edge xb
this is a great great pen i highly
recommend it
this is what i use to sketch by hand it
is probably the most commonly
used tool that i use highly recommended
um obviously you know i use a macbook
pro although i'll probably be switching
over to pc very soon
and those are pretty much the main tools
that i use it's
a pen and paper and my computer i think
that pretty much covers
the video if you found this video
helpful
please leave a like and subscribe it
does help me out if you want to buy
these books
click the links in the description below
once again it helps the channel out
it doesn't cost you anything extra and
it does help me out it gives me
you know a minor commission so i can
continue making these kinds of videos
anyway guys thank you so much for
checking out the video and i hope you
have a great day